<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Art | Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.yogeshn.com/categories/art/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.yogeshn.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-04T22:33:26+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.yogeshn.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[yn]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Artisan]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.yogeshn.com/2013/08/03/artisan/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-03T18:34:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.yogeshn.com/2013/08/03/artisan</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><strong>ar·ti·san</strong> [ahr-tuh-zuhn]</p>

<ol>
<li>a person skilled in an applied art; a craftsperson.</li>
<li>a person or company that makes a high-quality or distinctive product in small quantities, usually by hand or using traditional methods: our favorite local food artisans.</li>
</ol>
</blockquote>

<p>I have recently taken an interest in watching videos where craftsman in various trades ranging from calligraphy to woodwork make stuff.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> These aren&rsquo;t just videos of people quickly making things to quickly ship to their customers, these are people who have spent years working towards mastering their craft. These people are called <mark>Artisans</mark>.</p>

<p>These people spend their entire life crafting, taking time and perfecting each product they make. <mark>Taking time</mark> is something many people don&rsquo;t do when creating these days. Artisans don&rsquo;t even believe they have perfected at their job, they are always trying to improve. A good example here is of a 86 year old Sushi Chef called Jiro Ono. He is a master at Sushi with a 3 star Michelin restaurant. Even he is constantly learning, constantly looking for ways to improve, always challenging his own assumptions.</p>

<blockquote><p>Always look ahead and above yourself. Always try to improve on yourself. Always strive to elevate your craft. That’s what he taught me. – Yoshikazu Ono<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup></p></blockquote>

<p>Especially in the app world, there are too many people just putting things out there for no reason, they hurriedly write a piece of code or design something and put it out there as a finished product. This is wrong. Just because we now have tools that can speed up the process of creation doesn&rsquo;t mean we can&rsquo;t take the extra time to carefully think about how we can perfect it. <mark>The art of craftsmanship doesn&rsquo;t have to be lost.</mark></p>

<p>From all the people I consider to be a Artisan, they all have the following in common:</p>

<ul>
<li>incredibly patient</li>
<li>takes their time</li>
<li>prioritise quality rather than quantity</li>
<li>always learning to improve</li>
<li>picks the <a href="http://dcurt.is/the-best">best</a> of everything</li>
<li>loves their job</li>
</ul>


<p>Next time you decide to make something, take extra time crafting and re-crafting until it is perfect. You will almost definitely make something that sucks more than a few times. Spend time and think about why it sucks. You shouldn&rsquo;t be in a hurry to move on to the next iteration of your product. You will be spending your lifetime in this craft. It is time to do it correctly.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>I highly recommend <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/ArtisanVideos/">/r/ArtisanVideos/</a>.<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>Son of Jiro Ono who is being trained by Jiro. If you have time you should watch <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M-aGPniFvS0">Jiro Dreams of Sushi</a>.<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
